Santhosh R

Senior UI Developer

A passionate and competent UI developer with 11+ years of experience in building large scale and performance oriented applications from scratch. Looking for an opportunity to enable me to augment my acquired knowledge, bring to forefront my skills and offer opportunities for growth.



xashr17@gmail.com

Pengaluru, India

github.com/sashr17

+919738220304

in linkedin.com/in/santhosh-r-b5b41b21

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Associate

JP Morgan Chase & Co

01/2020 - Present

Responsibilities

Bengaluru, India

- Migrated Nostro Account Management application from Microsoft .Net to React eco-system from ground up and integrated with REST API's.
- Added reusable UI components and custom React hooks.
- Extensively used AG Grid and its features with unit tests.
- Troubleshooting and Team building.

Specialist SeniorDeloitte

10/2016 - 01/2020

Bengaluru, India

Responsibilities | Client: VMware

- Transformed VMware applications from Microsoft Sharepoint to Open source technology stack from scratch.
- Designed and Implemented component driven architecture.
- Integrated Social media and Chat support along with Adobe analytics.

Senior Software Engineer Ness Technologies

05/2015 - 09/2016

Bengaluru, India

Responsibilities | Client: CDK Global

- Revamped automotive retail market application.
- Developed reusable UI components using in-house Javascript framework.
- Handled API integrations, Unit tests and CD/CI process.

Senior Software Engineer

Harman (Symphony Teleca)

07/2014 - 05/2015

Bengaluru, India

Responsibilities | Client: NCR Corporation

- Revamped Supply chain product with HTML5/CSS3, Javascript and J2EE.
- Data migration and Troubleshooting.

Systems Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

07/2011 - 06/2014

Bengaluru, India

Responsibilities | Client: American Express

- Modernised Card Payment portal using HTML5/CSS3, jQuery and Ajax.
- Integrated Struts 2.0 framework, troubleshooting and release support.

SKILLS

JavaScript / ES6

React

Redux

HTML5

CSS

SASS

Git

Jest

React Testing Library

Kubernetes

AWS

AG-GRID

EDUCATION

B.E in Computer Science PES University

2007 - 2011 Bengaluru, India

CERTIFICATIONS

CKAD: Certified Kubernetes Application Developer ☑

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner 🗹

AWARDS

Spot Award - JP Morgan Chase & Co (05/2021)

For playing key role in migrating legacy application to React stack.

Spot Award - Deloitte (10/2019)

For conducting Node session for junior folks.

Applause Award - Deloitte (06/2017)

For playing key role in UI deliverables.